Finding Aid for the Bennet Harvive Branscomb Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Bennet, Harvive Branscomb
1894-1998
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0879
5.86 linear feet
When Harvie Branscomb (Alabama and Wadham '14) came to Vanderbilt in 1 946 ,it was a small private provincial institution. When he relinquished the Chancellorship in 1963, Vanderbilt was a modern, national university. The day after his election, Harvie wrote to a friend, "Vanderbilt has so far as I can find out,all the problems. It does not have enough money, nor enough room, nor enough buildings.
It has, however, a fine academic tradition." Later, in retrospect, he wrote, "It is clear that I was so convinced that the time had come to establish a great university in the part of the south where I had grown up, that the difficulties in doing it seemed vague and insubstantial in the bright glare of the influences, values and services which would flow from the kind of institution I dreamed of." Once installed as Vanderbilt's fourth Chancellor, Harvie Branscomb never looked back. In the seventeen years of his tenure, Vanderbilt would move into the elite circle of the top 20 universities in the country.
Harvie Branscomb was born in Huntsville, Alabama on Christmas day 1894, the son of Lewis and Nannie Branscomb. His father was a methodist minister. His early memories were dominated by the fixed routine of church life in a community that took for granted the truth of traditional Christianity as it was preached in the churches to which they all belonged. Harvie remembered clearly that his Father's interests were not so much in an evangelistic approach that would try to make saints of people, but in kindling their interests in social problems and political affairs and moral obligations. Harvie recalls that during his college years, he and his father spent many hours discussing critically what he studied and arguing vigorously about intel1ectuial. interests.
Having been graduated from Birmingham College,
Harvie left for Oxford weeks before the start of the First World War.
In the midst of his studies, Harvie and another Rhodes Scholar, Oliver Carmichael, who preceded him as Chancellor of Vanderbilt, volunteered for Herbert Hoover's Committee for Relief in Belgium. They were asked to carry a letter from Cardinal Mercier condemning the German invasion out of occupied Belgium. They were stopped and searched at the border, but with ingenuity and luck they were able to take the document through. For this they were later awarded the Med a i11e d u Ro i Albert, Med a i11e de La Re i ne (Belgium).
It was at Oxford the he became more interested in the personality of the historic Jesus. He became intrigued with the features of Judaism and the teachings of Jesus that had a common bond. He wrote two books, The Teach i ngs of Jesus and his dissertation,Jesus and the Law of Moses. He won the Canon Hall Greek Testament Prize, and was awarded a BA in Theology First Class with the verbal congratulations of the examiners.
With his studies at Oxford complete, Harvie returned to the US, served a brief stint in the Army, and joined the faculty of Southern Methodist University to teach New Testament.
The move to Dallas was important for an special reason. He met and married Margaret Vaughn. Theirs was a charmed meeting of two brilliand minds whose love of humanity, learning and beauty was extraordinary. From this point on, all that Harvie was to be professionally and personally was profoundly shaped by her faithful, delightful, and supportive presence. She died in 1991.
In 1925 at SMU, Harvie demonstrated his fierce support for academic freedom and free expression. It seemed that a young assistant professor, a protege of Harvie Branscomb, was causing a stir in the Methodist hierarchy with his provocative liberal lectures. After the young man was dismissed, Harvie wrote a letter to the local newspaper, disagreeing with the process and its conclusion. No sooner was it published than Harvie was "invited" to leave the institution, in spite of his later appeal to the Board of Trustees. Much later, Harvie wrote, "I hold no honorary degree with more pride than the one conferred on me by SMU some years after these events."
Following his brief stay at SMU, Harvie moved on to Duke, where he spent 21 years, first as a member of the faculty of the School of Religion, then ad Director of the Libraries, and ultimately as dean of the Divinity School.
In 1941 under sposorship of the Carnegie Corporation he published Teachi ng with Books, demonstrating that libraries were seen primarily as repositories for research materials and were little used in class rooms.
He was decorated by the Brazilian government with the Order of the Southern Cross for his work in reorganizing the National Library of Brazil, while serving as chairman of the American Library Association Mission to Brazil in 1 945.
When in 1946, Harvie Branscomb came to Vanderbilt, he would spend the next seventeen years building the vision he foresaw, and nourishing the academic tradition. Some astonishing things happened.
The University became a more diverse institution as students from all parts of the country were drawn to Vanderbilt, and in 1952 the doors were opened to minority students before the other private universities in the south took this step. Full-time student enrollment increased even as test scores and grades continued to rise.
During Chancellor Branscomb's tenure, the number of full-time faculty had doubled, faculty salaries had almost tripled and more buildings were built than had existed when he arrived. The university's annual budget had increased by more than 400% and the endowment had increased from $38 million in 1946 to $88 million in 1963.
He rebuilt the Medical School and revitalized the Medical Center, which was teetering on the edge of fiscal solvency. Between 1953 and 1963, the schools of Engineering, Divinity and Law acquired their own buildings. Fifteen new residency halls were built. Vanderbilt became a residential campus for undergraduates, which provided the campus culture that remains one of Vanderbilt's greatest strengths.
Harvie reasserted his interest in Brazil, opening up a research center that lives on to this day, and is now the intellectual home to some of Vanderbilt's finest scholars and teachers.
Under his leadership, Vanderbilt was elected to the Association of American Universities, the only member in the South between North Carolina and Texas. An important step was his ability to broaden the base of the Board of Trustees by attracting national figures as well as local leaders. Perhaps most important, was his recruitment of Harold Stirling Vanderbilt to be a part of the University his great-grandfather endowed but never saw. Harold Stirling would become President of the Board and later among the most generous philanthropists in Vanderbilt's history.
During the tumultuous 1 9 6 0 ' s, the James Lawson incident occurred. Lawson was a divinity student who participated vigorously in the civil disobedience of the sit-ins. The question of his expulsion arose. Harvie did not think he should be expelled, and brought the question for decision to the Board of Trustees. He counted on his leadership to persuade the Board not to expell Lawson. The Board did expell him. Later Harvie said he should have acted on the question himself. This experience chagrined him for the rest of his tenure.
Harvie found time to serve his country and higher education nationally. President Truman appointed him the first chairman of the US Advisory Commission for Education Exchange, which he led for four years. He later was named chairman of the Commission on Education and International Affairs of the American Council of Education. He advised the World Bank, the United Nations and other government agencies.
Harvie Branscomb's biography is a history of education in the 20th century, of its continued growth and lustre. Through his efforts and the fullfilment of his visions, Vanderbilt is no longer content with simply being good - it strives for greatness in everything it does.
Long after his retirement, Harvie Branscomb's presence in Nashville signified leadership and action.
People in all walks of life continued to seek his advice and social contact. He entertained and went out to social events right up to the time of his quiet peaceful death. About three months into his 104th year, he complained quite seriousle that he was having a harder time remembering names !
Chancellor Branscomb is survived by three sons, Harvie Branscomb, Jran attorney in Corpus Christi, Texas, Doctor Ben Branscomb, distinguished professor of medicine, at the University of Alabama Medical School, Birmingham, Alabama, and Lewis H. Branscomb, emeritus professor of public policy and corporate management at Harvard University and a member of Vanderbilt's Board of Trustees. He is also survived by nine grandchi1dren and nine great-grandchi1dren.
This strong, determined, scholar, theologian and educator will be sorely missed by his many colleagues world wide and by the numerous people upon whom he has left his rich mark of friendship and wisdom.
F .Tremai ne Bi11ings
(Pennsylvania and Balli o1 '33)
- Outgoing Correspondence Index
  Correspondence is listed chronologically. The folder number is indicated by the abbreviation F.
  - Feb. 7 to the Rockefeller Foundation; F 1., 1929 (Box 1)
  - Oct. 7 to Bishop Walter Peele; Oct. 29 to Bishop W.W. Peele; Nov. 8 to members of the North Carolina Conference; Nov. 29 to Prof. Albert Outler; Dec. 2 to Bishop W.W. Peele; F 1., 1946 (Box 1)
  - Nov. 7 to James E. Webb; FI., 1949 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 23 to Robert D. Calkins; May 30 to William Waller; Nov. 27 to Earl J. McGrath; F 1., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Nov. 1 to Henry Alexander; F 1., 1960 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 6 to Dr. J. Robert Nelson; Feb. 20 from Mrs. Collier Dawson (Secretary to the Chancellor) to Sam Fleming; Mar. 20 to Henry Alexander; May 29 to Baxter Jackson; June 22 to Harold Vanderbilt; July 4 to Harold Vanderbilt; July 7 to Harold Vanderbilt (typescript copy of July 4 letter); July 30 (copied Aug. 1) to Henry C. Alexander; Sept. 21 to Prof. Willard Jewell; Sept. 27 to Lillian Dorothy Cates; Nov. 1 to Willard Jewell; Dec. 18 to Willard Jewell; Dec. 18 to Robert Lester; Dec. 20 to Henry Alexander; F 1., 1961 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 29 to Henry C. Alexander; Feb. 20 to Henry Alexander; Mar. 2 to Henry Alexander; Mar. 5 to Henry Alexander; Mar. 9 to Richard C. Rowson; Apr. 26 to Henry Alexander; May 17 to Charles C. Trabue, Jr.; May 21 to Alfred Miller; May 30 to Weldon T. Ellis; Aug. 20 to Dr. J.L. Morrill; Sept. 17 to Richard H. Demuth; Nov. 13 to Richard DeMuth; Nov. 20 to George V. Allen; F 1., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Feb. 25 to Philip H. Coombs; Mar. 20 to J.E. Jonsson; Apr. 10 to Carlisle H. Humelsine; (May 28) to Bob (Nelson); June 28 to Grayson Kirk; July 1 to W. Allen Wallis; July 12 to May Davie (Mrs. Preston); Sept. 27 to Mrs. Preston Davie Nov. 4 to Rodney Jones; Nov. 27 to The Honorable Lucius D. Battle; Nov. 27 to I.L. Jones, Jr.; Nov. 27 to Arthur Minnich; Nov. 27 to Prof. Ewing Shahan; Dec. 19 to The Honorable William Ayres; Dec. 19 to The Honorable Edith Green; Dec. 19 to Senator Gale W. McGee; Dec. 19 to The Honorable Edward R. Murrow; F 1., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 31 to The Honorable Ellis Arnall; Mar. 18 to Harry Bober; Mar. 18 to Matthew G. Kayuza; Mar. 20 to P.N. Kirpal; Mar. 20 to Eugene M. Schaeffer; Mar. 24 to Dr. Malcumb Adeseshiah; Mar. 24 to Dr. Archibald MacLeish; Mar. 25 to Dr. Luther Terry; Mar. 25 (memo re: travel authorization for U.S. National Commission); Mar. 27 to Dr. Takajiro Inone; Mar. 27 to Senator A. Willis Robertson; Apr. 2 to Mrs. Lee Douglas (Marguerite); Apr. 8 to Dr. Frederick H. Burkhardt; Apr. 8 to Marcus Ginsburg; Apr. 18 to Prof. Walter Harrelson; Apr. 10 to Senator J. Caleb Boggs; Apr. 13 to Senator Gale McGee; Apr. 14 to The Honorable Harlan Cleveland; May 16 to Prof. William S. Dix; May 16 to Olive G. Turner; May 28 to Dr. Eugene H. Jacobson; June 12 to Rudolph Bares, Jr.; June 18 to Dr. Arthur Lawson; June 27 to Edwin Hughes; June 27 to Dr. Harold Spivacke; June 30 to Dr. 0. Meredith Wilson; Sept. 8 to Robert S. Lyle; Sept. 19 to Chancellor Alexander Heard; Sept. 28 to The Honorable Harlan Cleveland; Sept. 28 to The Honorable Harry C. McPherson, Jr.; Sept. 28 to Leonard C. Meeker; Oct. 30 to Malcolm S. Adiseshiah; Oct. 30 to Marcus Ginsburg; Dec. 2 to The Honorable Harry C. McPherson, Jr.; Nov. 13 to The Honorable Wladyslaw Grzedzielski; Nov. 15 to Prof. Athanase Joja; Nov. 17 memorandum to Senator Benton; Nov. 18 memorandum to Senator Benton; Dec. 27 to Veda Prakasha; Dec. 2 to Dr. Luther Terry; n.d. to Alan Pifer; F 1., 1964 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 6 to Dr. Paul J. Braisted; Jan. 7 to Honorable Stefan Wierblowski; Jan. 8 to Dr. Frederick H. Burkhardt; Jan. 8 to Mrs. Lawrence M.C. Smith; Jan. 8 to Dr. Mabel W. Smythe; Jan. 11 to Prof. Athanase Joja; Jan. 24 to Van Alen Holloman; Jan. 27 to Honorable Malcolm S. Adiseshiah; Jan. 29 to Ambassador Adlai E. Stevenson; Feb. 3 to Senator William Fulbright; Feb. 3 to Van Alen Holloman; Mar. 1 to Governor Frank Clement; Mar. 2 to Perrin C. Galpin; Mar. 2 to Grayson Kirk; Mar. 2 to Dr. Agustin Yanez; Mar. 4 to William Platt; Mar. 10 to Grayson Kirk; Mar. 10 to Allen A. Michie; Apr. 1 to Tom Ford; Apr. 2 to The Honorable Samuel J. Cookey; Apr. 5 to The Honorable Dean Rusk; Apr. 6 to Prof. Herbert W. Schneider; Apr. 7 to Senator J.W. Fulbright; Apr. 7 to Lawrence M.C. Smith; Apr. 9 to The Honorable Robert H.B. Wade; Apr. 9 to Dr. James Watt; Apr. 17 to The Honorable Dean Rusk; Apr. 19 to Dr. John H. Fisher; Apr. 19 to The Honorable Arthur W. Hummel, Jr,; Apr. 19 to Prof. Herbert Schneider; Apr. 28 to Robert Stanford; May 28 to Dr. Luther Terry; June 3 to Sidney G. Tickton; June 11 to Senator Ross Bass; June 11 to The Honorable Joe L. Evins; June 11 to Senator Albert Gore; June 11 to Prof. Athanase Joja; June 14 to F. William Beckinsale; July 19 to Robert P. Bass, Jr.; July 19 to Prof. John W. Hall; July 23 to President Lyndon B. Johnson; Aug. 6 to Marilyn Chelstrom; Aug. 6 to Dr. Herbert B. Pahl; Aug. 6 to Dr. S. John Reisman; Aug. 10 to Sidney G. Tickton; Oct. 7 to Ben Brodinsky; Oct. 7 to Dr. A. Hollis Edens; Oct. 7 to Henry L. Wright; Oct. 13 to Prof. Athanase Joja; Oct. 14 to Harold Vanderbilt; Oct. 15 to Eldon Dec. 22 to Clare M. Torrey; Dec. 23 to Dr. William H. Stewart; n.d. to educators re: UNESCO and International Cooperation Year; F 2., 1965 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 26 to Dr. Benjamin D. Blood; June 7 to Oris N. Treadwell; July 5 to Dr. Lawrence A. Kimpton; July 8 to The Honorable Dean Rusk; July 9 to The Honorable William Stewart; Aug. 5 to Arthur Minnich; Aug. 24 to Dr. Andrew G. Wallace; Aug. 24 to Dr. Margaret D. West; Aug. 26 to Mrs. Preston Davie; Aug. 26 to Dr. Margaret West; Sept. 23 to The Honorable Douglas Batson; Oct. 10 re: Johnston College; Oct. 14 to George H. Armacost; Nov. 15 to Honorable Carl B. Hyatt; Dec. 5 to Douglas Batson; Dec. 5 to Honorable Charles Frahkel; F 2., 1966 (Box 1)
  - Mar. 17 to George H. Armacost; Apr. 13 to Dr. Alvin C. Eurich; Apr. 13 to The Honorable Pardee Lowe; May 25 to Senator Howard A. Baker; May 25 to Mrs. J. Paschall Davis; May 25 to The Honorable Charles Frankel; ay 25 to Senator Gore; June 27 to Alvin C. Eurich; Aug. 5 to Mrs. Dexter 0. Arnold; Aug. 28 to Mrs. Fort Linton; Aug. 29 to Mrs. William Bradley; Aug. 29 to D.F. Gunnells; Aug. 29 to Dr. John H. Harris; Aug. 29 to Prof. F.H. Hazlehurst; Aug. 29 to Thomas Steele; Aug. 29 to Mrs. Willard Tirrill; Aug. 29 to Mrs. Robert White; Sept. 26 to members of the committee on the aims and objectives of Cheekwood; Oct. 30 to Justice Tom Clark; Oct. 30 to Dean Alex Domonkos; Oct. 30 to Dr. Lawrence A. Kimpton; Oct. 30 to Henry F. Lochte; Oct. 30 to Clare M. Torrey; Nov. 9 to The Honorable William B. Stevenson; Nov. 9 to Billy Sumner; Nov. 9 to Clare M. Torrey; Nov. 17 to Dr. William J. Bakrow; Nov. 17 to Justice Tom C. Clark; Nov. 17 to Lawrence A. Kimpton; Nov. 17 to L. Arthur Minnich; Dec. 6 re: UNESCO; F 2., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Mar. 6 to Judge Carl B. Hyatt; Mar. 18 to Chancellor Peter Sa Martino; May 7 to Judge Carl B. Hyatt; May 27 to Mrs. Preston Davie; Dec. 27 to Willard K. Laughlin; Dec. 27 to Harlan Matthews; F 2., 1968 (Box 1)
  - July 20 to James F. McClellan; F 2., 1970 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 17 to Henry Swint; F 2., 1972 (Box 1)
  - June 21 to Judge C.G. Neese; Nov. 1 to D. Bruce Shine; F 2., 1976 (Box 1)
  - May 18 to Dr. Hardy Liston; F 2., 1977 (Box 1)
  - Oct. 31 to Prof. Eason; F 2., 1978 (Box 1)
  - To Rex Moon; to Ambassador Alexei P. Pavlov; to Dr. William H. Stewart; F 2., Undated (Box 1)
- Incoming Correspondence Index
  The correspondence is listed alphabetically. The figure in parentheses immediately following each name indicates the total number of letters from that correspondent in the collection. The full name of the person is given whenever possible. The folder number is listed at the end of each entry preceded by the letter F.
  A
  Acheson, Dean, (1); Mar. 24, 1949; F 29.
  Adiseshiah, Malcolm S., (2); Oct. 29, 1964; F 26; Feb. 10, 1965; F 27.
  Alcott, James A., (1); Dec. 8, 1969; F 16.
  Allen, George V., (3); Mar. 17, Apr. 28, 1949; F 29; Nov. 5, 1962; F 26.
  Allen, Helen A., (3); Oct. 27, Dec. 15, 1976, Apr. 1, 1977; F 25.
  Alexander, Henry C., (3); Nov. 9, 1960, Feb. 10, 1962, Feb. 20, 1962 (Memorandum with enclosures); F 32.
  Alexander, Ridley, (1); Nov. 21, 1967 (also signed by Bill Brock, Richard Fulton, Frank C. Gorrell, Cecil C. Humphreys, Edwin 0. Norris); F 14.
  Anderson, Bettina, (1); Mar. 2, 1965; F 13.
  Anderson, Donald G, (1); Mar. 4, 1948; F 3.
  Anderson, Robert Nelson, (2); June 18, 1968, June 2, 1969; F 19.
  Armacost, George H., (2); Aug. 24, Oct. 17, 1966; F 4.
  Arnall, Ellis, (1); Apr. 8, 1964; F 26.
  Atterbury, Boudinot P., (1); Jan. 23, 1968; F 19.
  B
  Bailey, Robert H., (2); Mar. 1, May 10, 1977; F 25.
  Bakrow, William J., (6); Nov. 14, Nov. 20, 1967, Jan. 26, July 30, 1968, May 20, 1969, n.d.; F 18.
  Bares, Rudolph, Jr., (1); June 4, 1964; F 10.
  Bass, Robert P., Jr., (1); May 27, 1965; F 27.
  Batson, Douglas N., (6); July 8, 1965, Oct. 26, 1965, Nov. 12, 1965; F 22; Aug. 31, Nov. 17, 1966, Jan. 27, 1967 (addressed to Dr. Thomas F. Malone); F 22.
  Batson, Randolph, (1); Mar. 8, 1966 (with enclosure); F 30.
  Battle, Lucius D., (2); Nov. 15, 1963; F 3; June 29, 1964; F 26.
  Baumann, Carol Edler, (1); July 15, 1965; F 27.
  Beckinsale, F. William, (2); May 24, June 3, 1965; F 13.
  Bellinger, Frederick, (1); May 7, 1964; F 26.
  Benedict, Andrew, (2); Oct. 7, 1946, July 2, 1973; F 33.
  Benton, John Keith, (1); Apr. 28, 1953; F 33.
  Benton, William, (2); Nov. 18, 1964; F 21; Oct. 25, 1965; F 27.
  Berve, Nancy M. (2); Jan. 20, Jan. 23, 1969 (addressed to Rexford G. Moon, Jr. F 4.
  Betancour-Mejia, Gabriel, (1); Jan. 17, 1964; F 26.
  Bigwood, E.J., (2); May 8, 1965 (addressed to friends and alumni of BAEF), July 18, 1965 (addressed to Sidney A. Mitchell); F 9
  Binns, Josephine, (1); July 4, 1967; F 23.
  Bitker, Bruno V., (1); July 14, 1965; F 27.
  Bing, Peter S., (1); Oct. 15, 1965; F 30.
  Blood, Benjamin D., (2); Jan. 19, Mar. 15, 1966; F 30.
  Bober, Harry, (7); June 2, 1964, Dec. 6, 1965, Mar. 22, Apr. 4, July 20, Aug. 26, 1966, Apr. 1969 (addressed to members); F 9.
  Boggs, J. Caleb, (1); Apr. 15, 1964; F 26.
  Bogue, E. Grady, (1); July 5, 1977 (addressed to Dr. Paul Sands); F 24.
  Bolden, Wiley S., (1); Aug. 29, 1969; F 4.
  Bradley, Mrs. W.T., (1); Sept. 12, 1967; F 23.
  Bragg, John T., (1); Oct. 6, 1967 (statement to the Joint Committee on Constitutional Revision of the 85th General Assembly); F 14.
  Braisted, Paul J., (6); Nov. 14, 1963 (addressed to M. Rene Maheu), Dec. 31, 1963, July 1, Dec. 10, 1964; F 21; Aug. 16, Sept. 16, 1965; F 27.
  Brock, Joseph H., (1); June 6, 1962; F 32.
  Brodinsky, Ben, (2); Apr. 27, Oct. 2, 1965; F 27.
  Brown, Wayne, (1); Mar. 7, 1977; F 24.
  Bryan, E.D., (5); July 13, 1965 (addressed to Michael Rapuano), July 13, 1965 (addressed to E.S. Gardner), July 13, 1965 (addressed to William Platt), July 15, 1965 (addressed to Arch Boone), Aug. 9, 1965 (addressed to E.C. Roberts); F 35.
  Butterfield, Victor, (1); Sept. 19, 1966; F 6.
  Byrd, Benjamin F., Jr., (1); Aug. 1, 1973; F 23.
  C
  Cale, Edgar B., (1); Apr. 22, 1969; F 18.
  Carmichael, Mike, (1); Jan. 3, 1950; F 33.
  Carson, Van, (1); Nov. 24, 1970 (addressed to Alfred E. Thomas); F 18.
  Cates, Lillian Dorothy, (3); Sept. 22, Sept. 29, Oct. 3, 1961; F 32.
  Champion, George, (2); Feb. 14, 1961 (addressed to Sam M. Fleming), Mar. 3, 1961 (addressed to Sam M. Fleming); F 30.
  Chatenay, L. Peter, (1); Sept. 27, 1962; F 35.
  Chelstrom, Marilyn, (1); July 30, 1965; F 21.
  Chiappetta, Michael, (1); Dec. 30, 1964; F 26.
  Cikins, Warren I., (1); Aug. 20, 1969; F 19.
  Clark, Tom C., (7); June 10, 1966 (addressed to Executive Officers), June 10, 1966 (addressed to the Mayor), June 13, Nov. 9, Nov. 13, 1967, May 21, 1969, n.d.; F 19.
  Clement, Frank G., (2); Nov. 8, 1963, Dec. 30, 1964 (memorandum addressed to members of the Board of Trust of the Cordell Hull Foundation); F 12.
  Cleveland, Harlan, (1); Apr. 29, 1965; F 27.
  Cole, Jim, (1); Oct. 29, 1968 (addressed to Rexford G. Moon, Jr.); F 4.
  Colligan, Francis J., (1); June 30, 1950; F 29.
  Connor, Thomas K., (2); Dec. 1, 1969, Jan. 9, 1970; F 6.
  Cooky, S.J., (1); Apr. 23, 1965; F 27.
  Cox, Charles H., (1); Mar. 24, 1967; F 19.
  Crawford, Nancy, (1); Apr. 25, 1968; F 14.
  D
  Davie, May, (8); Sept. 2, 1966, Apr. 27, Oct. 18, Nov. 10, 1967, Apr. 29, May 13, 1968, May 2, 1969, June 1, 1973; F 21.
  Davis, Mrs. J. Paschall, (3); May 29, 1968, May 21, 1969, May 11, 197(?); F 20.
  Davis, W.L., (1); May 28, 1962; F 32.
  Dempsey, Edward W.; (1); Apr. 7, 1964 (addressed to Dr. Luther Terry); F 30.
  Demuth, Richard H., (2); Sept. 6, 1962, Oct. 31, 1963; F 35.
  Dix, William S., (2); Sept. 16, 1963, Apr. 23, 1964; F 26.
  Dolley, Robert D., (1); Mar. 20, 1965 (addressed to Thomas Ford); F 13.
  Dvorak, Raymond F., (1); June 7, 1972; F 15.
  E
  Eason, Douglas 0., (1); July 30, 1979; F 24.
  Edens, A. Hollis, (1); Sept. 8, 1965; F 27.
  Elliott, Charles, Jr., (1); Apr. 25, 1965; F 23.
  Elliott, William Y., (2); Jan. 30, 1961 (addressed to Kenneth Holland), Feb. 7, 1961; F 32.
  Ellis, Weldon T., (1); May 24, 1962; F 30.
  Eurich, Alvin C., (9); Feb. 7, 1966, Apr. 10, June 22, 1967, Jan. 24, Sept. 18, Sept. 25, Nov. 7, Dec. 17, 1968, Sept. 25, 1969, Mar. 12, 1975; F 4.
  Everton, John Scott, (1); Dec. 15, 1964; F 26.
  F
  Fisher, John Hurt, (1); Apr. 26, 1965; F 27.
  Fleming, Sam M., (2); Feb. 17, Mar. 6, 1961; F 30.
  Frankel, Charles, (2); May 23, May 31, 1967; F 22.
  Fulbright, J.W., (2); Feb. 8, Apr. 26, 1965; F 27.
  G
  Gallinger, William D., (1); Mar. 20, 1969; F 18.
  Galloway, C.B., (1); Oct. 17, 1972; F 15.
  Galpin, Perrin C., (2); Feb. 1, 1965 (addressed to members); Jan. 16, 1966, Jan. 16, 1966; F 9.
  Garner, R.L., (2); Nov. 7, 1960, Aug. 11, 1961 (addressed to Henry C. Alexander); F 32.
  Garnsey, Morris E., (1); Jan. 5, 1967; F 9.
  Gehrig, Leo D., (1); Mar. 21, 1966; F 30.
  Gerbner, George, (1); June 1, 1965 (addressed to Lawrence M.C. Smith); F 27.
  Ginsberg, Marcus, (3); Apr. 6, Oct. 28, 1964, n.d.; F 26.
  Gore, Albert, (1); June 25, 1965; F 27.
  Green, Edith, (1); Nov. 12, 1963; F 26.
  Grisham, Frank P., (1); Dec. 14, 1977; F 33.
  Grundfest, Jerry, (1); Jan. 13, 1976; F 15.
  Grzedzielski, Wladyslaw, (1); (Christmas card, 1965); F 27.
  Gunnells, D.F., (1); Sept. 1, 1967; F 23.
  Gwinn, Robert L., (1); Apr. 18, 1969 (addressed to Billy T. Sumner); F 23.
  H
  Hagel, Raymond C., (1); Sept. 23, 1969; F 16.
  Harari, Maurice, (2); Apr. 15, Apr. 20, 1965 (enclosed copy of report on Mission to India - Mar. 12-28, 1965); F 13.